Advanced Class
Jan. 14th (Tues.)
Class Duty: Minazuki
Isaki and I are thinking
of becoming two separate humans.
Separate humans?
Yes.
At first, the plan was
to become one human,
to stop living a halfhearted
existence as a werewolf...
But after talking things over,
we don't see a need to merge
into a single personality.
Does that mean you'll
each have your own body?
Yes.
Is that even possible?!
When we enrolled, the director
told us that was an option.
Really?
I used to think it'd be better
if I didn't exist.
But after starting
an exchange diary with Isaki,
we want to be there for each other.
I see.
Sure, I'll discuss it
with the principal and director.
Thank you very much!
So what will you do
after you become humans?
Until now, you were planning to enter
a private liberal arts university.
But now with two Ohgamis
in need of a career path...
Huh?
Eh?
Oh, no, Mr. Hitoma.
I didn't think about that at all!
Ah...
Episode 6
The Misanthrope and the Light of Dawn
Jan. 17th (Fri.)
Class Duty: Usami
Okay,
let's talk about the final
assignments for the advanced class.
In order to graduate and become human,
you need to pass the final assignment.
The principal and director will prepare
a personalized task for each of you.
None of that matters to me.
I got 150 points deducted
for sneaking off campus.
So there's no point in doing
the final assignment.
"The final assignment
is meant to challenge you
in ways that a class can't teach."
Or so the principal said.
Graduation or not,
you'll have to do the assignment.
You have until the end
of February to submit it.
I want you all to do
your best to complete it.
We've just received our final
assignments from the principal.
Mine is to hunt down
one of the director's gems.
A treasure hunt?
This contains hints to the gem's location.
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
Oh? Now that sounds like a fun time.
As for me,
I have to collect the signatures of
every enrolled student and faculty member.
Signatures?
So they just write down their names?
They're treating me like I'm stupid.
This should be easy.
Mine is writing the sports anthem
for our field day next year.
Sounds perfect
for a music lover like you.
I have to write a 20,000-character novella
with a cast of five or more people.
None of the assignments
seem overly difficult.
Instead of the end of February,
we might see everyone finish in January.
Jan. 24th (Fri.)
Class Duty: Minazuki
How are you all doing
on your final assignments?
Pretty good, if you ask me.
I'm done with the melody
and the lyrics for the chorus.
You're working on the lyrics
and music at the same time?
I wanted to nail the chorus first
since it's the key part,
and then build out the rest from there.
Huh, now that's an interesting approach.
How about you, Usami?
I've already talked to every student.
But it's impossible.
What do you mean?
Take a look.
Are these... paw prints?
The beginner class is still getting
used to their human forms,
and a lot of the students can't write yet.
I got their paw prints, but the principal
said they don't count as signatures.
The beginner class won't be easy...
How are you doing, Ohgami?
Why would they say this?
Why? I can't understand how they feel!
Sounds like you're struggling, too.
How's your assignment going, Minazuki?
The first hint was a crossword puzzle,
which I found hard but managed to solve.
I see.
The next one's just as difficult,
and I'm still figuring it out.
I'm sure I'll manage to get it, though!
Since I solved the first one.
Yeah.
There's still more than a month left.
Don't stress out and panic.
Just keep on chipping away. Got it?
Yes!
Jan. 31st (Fri.)
Class Duty: Ohgami
There we go!
Music and lyrics, all done!
I'm glad to hear it, Haneda.
Once I show it to the principal and
get his okay, I'll finish the assignment!
Splendid work, Tobari!
You did it! You're the first one!
I'm mad that you beat me to it.
Still, congratulations.
Thanks. How are you all doing?
I'm giving lessons every day for the
beginner class to teach them to write.
My story's over 20,000 characters now.
You sure did work hard, Ohgami.
So you're done now?
Actually, the plot's gotten too big!
What?
The cast has taken on a mind of their own,
with no ending in sight
after 20,000 characters!
I don't know when I'll ever finish!
I see. That sounds rough.
What about you, Kyoka?
I'm ashamed to say
that I've made no progress.
I see. Want me to help?
No, that won't be necessary.
This is my assignment.
I'll see through it all by myself.
Got it.
Well, let us know if you need anything.
We're here to help.
Thank you for your concern.
Feb. 7th (Fri.)
Class Duty: Minazuki
I've finished!
A novella with a minimum of 20,000
characters and a cast of five or more!
It's complete!
The final character count is 38,033!
Good job, Ohgami.
I think I might enjoy
coming up with stories.
That's great!
It's embarrassing to ask,
but would you care to read it?
Sure!
Feb. 14th (Fri.)
Class Duty: Usami
Signature Book
Sui Usami
I'm done...
I spent so much time teaching them
to write, day in and day out.
Some ran away.
Some were scared.
Some set up traps for me.
What a royal pain.
I see. You worked really hard.
Um...
Kyoka, how's your assignment going?
I mean, if there's anything I can do,
please don't hesitate to ask for help!
You're too kind.
That said, it's my assignment,
so I'll do my best by myself.
I learned the hard way!
If you don't put your feelings into words,
they won't get through!
So perhaps I may be acting out of line...
But if you need help,
feel free to ask at any time!
Yes, I'll ask when the time is right.
Kyoka!
Tell me what part
you're having trouble with!
I'll help you out!
Thank you for offering.
However, this assignment is
for me to solve, so I'll be just fine.
I can tell it's fake.
What?
I've never liked the way you smile.
It reminds me of the person I love,
forcing a smile on her face.
I simply hold pride
in always staying positive.
Forced as it may be, it is my wish
to challenge myself and overcome this.
So there's no problem at all.
That attitude's what ticks me off!
Usami.
It's fine, Mr. Hitoma.
Is the point of this assignment
not to overcome it yourself?
I appreciate the concern you've shown me,
but please understand.
You always try and handle
everything on your own.
Will you be able to ask for help
when you really need it?
I...
I have no need for your help.
Feb. 21st (Fri.)
Class Duty: Haneda
One week left until the deadline.
Will Minazuki be okay?
Mr. Hitoma!
Morning!
Ah, Ohgami.
Wait, is today the full moon?
Kyoka and Ushami are fighting, no cap?
What do you make
of the situation with Kyoka?
I think it's important to admit
when you can't do something by yourself.
I see...
In that case...
Mr. Hitoma, you ever takopa'd?
Takopa?
I couldn't find octopus on short notice,
so there's konjac in it instead.
There isn't any seafood in konjac,
so I can eat without hesitation.
The idea's that if you chat while
cooking and eating all together,
you can ask about real
heavy stuff, no prob!
No prob, huh?
Plan number one.
Make Kyoka think that I have zero clue,
and figure out where she's stuck.
Hey, how's the assignment going, Kyoka?
Right off the bat?!
I'd say I'm making progress.
Oh, for real?
What's your assignment, anyway?
Mine is a treasure hunt.
Sounds like fun!
What do you do?
You solve puzzles one by one.
So it's not just one problem?
That's right.
The first one was a crossword puzzle,
and the solution was "Gotemba".
Final Assignment
Isaki's heard of that!
They have an outlet mall there!
And? What's the second problem?
Oh, well, you see...
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
Wait, is the second
one, like, super hard?!
Some kinda crazy math problem?
Isaki just can't with math!
The second appears
to be some sort of riddle.
It says...
Final Assignment   Problem 2
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
Try and remember!
The very first class!
And when you trace them in order...?
Try and remember.
The very first class.
And when you trace them in order...
That's what it says.
I looked up the first class for beginner,
intermediate, and advanced levels,
but I couldn't figure it out.
What was our first class
for the beginner level?
A tour of the school.
After the tour, they handed out
a hiragana worksheet.
And then we introduced ourselves.
The beginner class starts by learning
about writing and speaking.
That's right.
Kyoka, do you remember
our first introductions?
Our first introductions?
Your name and the reason
you want to be human.
I want to become human to repay
the kindness a human showed me.
That's why I also want to
help the people around me.
And so...
Kyoka, I'm sorry about what I said!
What?
I wasn't thinking about how you felt,
wanting to do your best.
I just wanted to help.
For my own satisfaction.
Usami...
No, don't say that.
You're not at fault here, Usami.
I should also...
Well...
Minazuki.
You know...
I can't do anything
without depending on others.
Even for stuff I was asked to do,
I often find I can't do it alone.
I think it's a really important skill to
be able to ask others when that happens.
No human can survive all on their own.
We bother those around us,
as they bother us.
Life is all about supporting
each other in that way.
Is it really all right?
Would it be all right for me to ask you
for your precious time?
I already said it was okay.
Fine by me as well.
Yeah! You betcha!
Everyone...
Oh, don't forget I'm here, too.
That goes without saying, Mr. Hitoma!
Everyone, please lend me your assistance!
Yeah!
Final Assignment   Problem 1
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
Solve the
crossword puzzle!
The answer to the first
problem was Gotemba.
The key phrases for problem two
are "the very first class",
and "when you trace them in order".
What could it mean?
Since I was teaching
the beginner class kids,
I have the very first
printouts they give you.
Hiragana Table
A map of the school and a hiragana chart.
What are you supposed to trace in order?
Could it be the solution
to the crossword puzzle?
Ko
Go-te-m-ba.
Ha
There.
Hiragana Table
Wait!
Could it be?
Hiragana Table
Ha
Te
Ko
N
So that's what it was!
Science Prep Room
Let us go and take a look!
Excuse us.
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
So somewhere in here...
Here it is!
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
Kyoka Minazuki. Final assignment.
That's it!
Office
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
Found it!
Here!
Final Assignment
Kyoka Minazuki
I found it!
Advanced class student
Teacher
Location from a dream
A certain
love story
A certain love story.
Location from a dream.
Teacher.
Advanced class student.
What do they mean?
Could one of us here be
harboring feelings for Mr. Hitoma?
Hey, wait. That can't be it.
What's the next thing it says?
Final Assignment   Problem 3
m 0 0 l 230 0 l 230 215 l 0 215
Where was the confession?
The final problem asks,
"Where was the confession?"
What?!
Isaki, does that ring a bell?
I-I-Isaki?!
I-If you ask Isaki...
Well...
Mr. Hitoma...
What?!
Wait, did you and Isaki...
I don't know what you're thinking,
but you're wrong!
At least I think so!
Hey! You say something, too, Ohgami!
Isaki can't talk here...
Why not?!
This is Isaki we're
talking about, not Isaki!
Isaki can't just go blabbing about it!
What's this all about?
Actually, the novel that Isaki wrote
for her graduation assignment...
Isaki can't say any more!
Isaki will go back to being
Isaki tomorrow, so ask Isaki then!
In my novel, it took place
under the cherry tree.
Let's all look for it!
Time to hunt for treasure!
Hey, wait, everyone!
Make sure you don't go
beyond the cherry tree!
Minazuki!
I see it. Up there!
A treasure chest.
It sure is high up.
Will it come falling down if we shake it?
Let me give it a try.
There!
You suck.
How about we throw something at it?
Like a game of darts or target practice.
That's an excellent suggestion!
Excuse me.
Could I possibly impose upon you to use
that feather to knock the chest down?
That's no good!
How could you?!
No need to be so formal.
Ask a little more casually,
and I'd be happy to.
Casually?
You sounded so pompous,
it caught me off guard.
Pompous?
Tobari, can you grab that box for me?
Sure thing!
Okay, here goes nothing.
Yes!
There!
You did it!
Oh, no! The barrier!
Minazuki, stop!
Mr. Hitoma!
Are you hurt?
No, I'm fine.
The box is safe as well!
Thank you so much.
Congratulations!
Looks like everyone in the advanced class
has finished their final assignments!
Principal, my apologies
for taking so long.
I would not have been able to
complete this assignment alone.
However, I was able to see it through
thanks to my wonderful friends.
As such...
Please distribute my points equally among
the four of us in our class.
Once again...
Congratulations!
With this, all of your graduation
assignments have been submitted.
And we have decided which students meet
the requirements to graduate.
We will have one student
graduating this year.
She has no violations on record,
and has consistently acquired points.
A student with the clear academic
and social skills to survive among humans.
However, she could never muster
the courage to rely on others.
A student adamant on doing
everything by herself.
But by relying on others
for her graduation assignment,
she finally learned to become a bother.
For these reasons stated,
the one graduating will be...
Kyoka Minazuki.
You're the one.
Thank you very much!
Next Episode:
The Misanthrope and the Fruitless Love Fortune